

Ashish Kumar

"Solution Engineer"

- kumar1010ashish@gmail.com
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/ashishkumar-3497485a/
- Marathahalli Sarjapur Outer Ring Rd, Kadubeesanahalli, Bengaluru, 560037 Bangalore, India
- 9148100729
- https://ashisharyan1993.github.io/learninglibrary/

Profile

DevOps Engineer/Oracle database Pre-sales with 6 years of total experience in Micro-services architecture, Oracle Cloud Infrastructure (OCI) services, Terraform, Kubernetes (OKE), Docker, Splunk along with the knowledge of Node.js, Git, JSON, Regex, Appdynamics, OMC, OEM, Oracle Database, etc

Skills

Docker

Terraform

Splunk

AppDynamics

Oracle Management Cloud

Oracle Enterprise Manager

Oracle/AWS Cloud

DevOps Tool

Professional Experience

Solution Engineer, Oracle India Private Ltd

- Experienced as a DevOps Engineer into oracle cloud infrastructure support with different DevOps tools like Terraform, Docker, Kubernetes (OKE) and Oracle Cloud Services.
- Provided Support for version control system tools like GIT for branching, tagging and source code management.
- Experience in Oracle/AWS Cloud Technology various modules Object/S₃, Compute/EC₂, Function/LAMBDA, IAM, Other Cloud Services.
- Provided Support for Docker for the microservice architecture of the application with Oracle Database.
- Automated several processes by using Terraform and shell script.
- Troubleshoot and resolve issues in Development, QA and Production environments.
- Experience in Unix/Linux utilities using tools like Putty, WinSCP for analyzing logs, and troubleshooting application issues.
- Hands-on experience with Agile Methodology.

Working with Pre-Sales organization as a Solution Engineer for Oracle Management Cloud and Oracle Enterprise Manager, A suite of next-generation integrated monitoring, management and analytics solutions delivered as a service on Oracle Cloud. Responsible for working closely with Sales & Customer Success Teams understanding Customer's Enterprise Monitoring Requirements. Running Discovery Sessions with multiple teams and stakeholders, understanding the KPI's to suggest and build Solutions that deliver the purpose, adds value to Customer Investments and help the Implementation teams build Great success stories.

12/2018 – present Bangalore, India

IT Analyst, Tata Consultancy Services

08/2015 – 12/2018 Bangalore, India

- Conducted installation, configuration, integration and architecture maintenance of different tools like Splunk (bigdata log analytics), Appdynamics(APM) and Moogsoft AIOPS(Event Management System) in both on-premise and AWS environments.
- Handled onboarding of new projects and applications into existing Splunk-Appd-Moogsoft infrastructure.
- Investigated both structured and unstructured machine and transaction logs.
- Extracted baseline, business intelligence, customer behaviour and patterns; and identify trends by predictive analysis.
- Performed APM and identified failures, errors and anomalies.
- Implemented mathematical analysis on transaction failure and success scenarios and determining thresholds and set up alerts, health rules, dashboards and reports as required.
- Automated repetitive and manual tasks using JavaScript, SQL and SPL.
- Created interactive dashboards (using XMLs), form searches and reports.
- Created different ad-hoc and scheduled alerts according to business requirements using SPL (Splunk Processing Language) Implemented techniques like macros and knowledge objects like event types, tags, field extractions, lookups, saved searches, transactions, fields etc.
- Implemented techniques like macros and knowledge objects like event types, tags, field extractions, lookups, saved searches, transactions, fields etc.
- Familiar with DB Connect App, Website Monitoring tool, KAFKA and other Splunk Add-ons.
- Familiar with data models, pivots, Clustering (Indexer and search head).
- Familiar with different configuration files in splunk like inputs, outputs, savedsearches, props, transforms, indexes, meta, authentication, data models, deployment client, server, eventtypes, serverclass, fields, etc.

Languages

Hindi • English

E Certificates

• Oracle Cloud Infrastructure 2020

• Splunk - Power User

Education

BE - Electrical & Electronics Engineering (EEE), Siddaganga Institute of Technology

2011 – 2015 Tumkuru, India

10th/12th CBSE, Kendriya Vidyalaya Jamalpur

2010 Jamalpur, India

"I hereby declare that all the details mentioned above are in accordance with the truth and fact as per my knowledge and I hold the responsibility for the correctness of the above-mentioned particulars."

Ashish KumarBangalore